[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 15]
[Princess Ying's Mansion]
Deputy Minister Zhang is here.
Stand still. Don't move.
Wait.
[Princess Ying's Mansion]
Stop!
Release him.
[Princess Ying's Mansion]
In broad daylight,
you're still trying to abduct someone?
How is this abduction?
I simply sent someone
to invite him as a guest.
Your Highness,
since he's a guest,
he should be free to come and go.
It's clear that this gentleman
no longer wants to be here.
A mere personal matter
has disturbed Deputy Minister Zhang.
I wonder what kind of relationship
between you and Mr. Han.
Your Highness,
I was ordered to express condolences
to the Grand Commander and his wife.
I just happened to hear about this from
the Grand Commander's wife.
The Grand Empress Dowager has always valued you.
My doing
is also for your own good.
I hope you'll reconsider, Your Highness.
[Princess Ying's Mansion]
Since you've already spoken,
I won't force him to stay as a guest.
[Princess Ying's Mansion]
I shall take my leave now.
Mrs. Shen,
I have made myself clear last time.
You may be able to protect Han for now,
but can you protect him forever?
[Princess Ying's Mansion]
Grand Commander,
I've just received a report.
Multiple moth-shaped jade pieces
have appeared
in the ruins of Jinxiu Workshop,
and some familiar faces have shown up.
It's very strange.
Let's go
to Jinxiu Workshop.
It's Mr. Kong, the shopkeeper of Jinxiu Workshop.
Isn't he already dead?
Is it a person or a ghost?
Could it be that the dead can really come back to life?
You saw it just now, didn't you?
Could it really be the work of a spirit?
I never believe
in ghosts or gods.
If there were,
it would be someone secretly causing mischief.
If we investigate carefully,
we'll surely find some clues.
I've found it!
The divine signs have revealed the jade.
This moth-shaped jade must be divine jade!
-There must be more!
-Find it.
-I'm sure there's more!
-Find it!
I found one!
Amazing!
I found another one.
[Shen's Mansion]
I have a feeling
that behind this case
there are two powerful forces.
One force
wants to quietly erase
the Jinxiu Workshop case,
while the other
is stirring up trouble for their own gain.
The moth-shaped jade.
The workshop owner's spirit.
The dead coming back to life.
All these bizarre events
seem to have been planned
to happen this month.
To stir up such turmoil
in the Imperial City,
it's not something a common
murderer or sorcerer
could do.
There must be powerful figures behind this.
But I just can't figure out
this powerful figure's
purpose.
Deification.
Deification?
The current situation of this case
is no longer something
within your control.
There are cases within the case,
and it's intricately linked
to the political struggles in the court.
Then why is the killer
trying to create a deity?
What do you think?
My only thought now,
which is also my only advice to you,
is to stop investigating.
Don't bring trouble upon yourself.
Boring.
I thought
you might have some real insights.
I must continue
investigating this case.
How naive.
Don't recklessly
put yourself in danger.
Are you...
actually concerned about me?
What do you think?
Anyway,
you're now bearing
the title of the Grand Commander's wife.
Behave yourself,
and don't get
yourself involved in this.
I still think you're concerned about me.
You won't let me go,
but I insist on
getting to the bottom of this.
Madam.
Lu Chuichui and I
have an appointment at the silk shop in the south of the city.
I heard they've got a new batch of fabrics.
There are madder red,
iris yellow,
oak black,
and locust yellow.
The tie-dyeing is so beautiful.
I'm afraid they'll be sold out if I'm late.
Why don't you go back first?
Don't disturb the Grand Commander.
He didn't rest well last night.
Let him sleep a bit longer.
Alright.
Go on, go on.
Madam, you're up so early.
Where are you heading?
Lu Chuichui and I have an appointment
at the silk shop in the south of the city
to see a new batch of fabrics.
There are madder red,
iris yellow,
oak black,
and locust yellow.
The tie-dyeing is so beautiful.
I'm afraid they'll be sold out if we're late.
I need to go to
a silk shop in the south of the city.
I heard they've got a new batch of fabrics.
Uncle Zhong,
what's going on?
Iris yellow,
oak black,
and locust yellow.
Did she argue with the Grand Commander again?
I'm afraid they'll be sold out if we're late.
What are you talking about?
Would you like some sugar cakes?
I just made them.
I was about to take them to the Grand Commander.
No,
it's a made-up lie.
What?
Mrs. Shen rushed out
so early in the morning.
She must have some urgent business.
I've noticed that the Grand Commander
hasn't had much appetite for breakfast these days.
So I made some sugar cakes.
Why don't you try some too?
Jing Lin.
Grand Commander.
Go and keep an eye on Yan Xing.
Given her temperament,
she definitely won't listen to me.
Yes.
While reviewing the entire case,
we overlooked someone.
There was another witness
who found
Chen's body
besides Chen Shoujie.
She personally cooked,
making water-boiled mutton and smoked chicken.
She also baked flatbread and pilaf.
She even rewarded this old servant with a bowl of wine.
How kind the madam is to us.
That night, she personally cooked,
making water-boiled mutton and smoked chicken.
She also baked flatbread and pilaf.
The servant of Chen Shoujie—
his testimony was exactly
the same as what the officials recorded
when they questioned him.
The two statements were word-for-word identical.
[Not entering the cycle of reincarnation. Immortal reincarnation]
I'm afraid he had memorized
what to say beforehand.
Chen Shoujie.
Where's your old servant?
Fire moths, fire moths.
Fire moths.
What fire moths?
Fire moths! Fire moths! Fire moths!
Fire moths!
It's you.
On the day Mrs. Chen was killed,
what exactly did you see?
Why did you fabricate your testimony?
[Chen's Mansion]
It seems like he's waiting for me.
[Mingsheng Temple]
Mingsheng Temple.
Sounds familiar.
Excuse me,
did you see
anyone come in just now?
Excuse me...
Help!
Back from the dead.
Back from...
You can't die.
You haven't told me yet
who the murderer is.
-You can't die!
-Who are you?
And who are you?
Why did you kill him?
I didn't kill him.
I saw it with my own eyes.
You still want to deny it?
I really didn't kill him.
Guards!
I didn't kill him.
I just...
Stop!
Greetings, Princess Runing.
Princess Runing?
[Mingsheng Temple]
Mingsheng Temple.
No wonder it sounds so familiar.
Princess Runing,
implicated in the Jinxiu Workshop case,
is reflecting at Mingsheng Temple.
Xu.
What?
Do you want to lose your head?
Or your hands?
How could I be so stupid?
I've been set up,
and fallen into a trap.
I'm such a fool.
What happened?
This powder...
I must have gotten it on me
in Mingsheng Temple.
It looks like
the suspicious powder
around Jinxiu Workshop.
I need to calm down and think.
There must be some connection.
There must be something
I've overlooked.
Don't worry.
Right now, there's
someone even more anxious than you outside.
I followed all the way,
but my horse
seemed to be frightened
when I reached Chen Shoujie's residence.
By the time I arrived
at Mingsheng Temple,
Princess Runing had already...
Are you sure Yan Xing was acting strangely
after leaving Chen's Mansion?
Yes,
I called out to Madam several times,
but she didn't respond at all.
She seemed bewitched,
chasing after something.
I don't care who it is,
but whoever dares
to target my people,
they'll regret it.
But Madam was taken
by Princess Runing.
This matter might not be so simple.
There are rules.
You can't go in.
How could Yan Xing possibly kill someone?
You really can't go in.
How is Yan Xing?
She's fine.
She just ate two steamed buns.
By the way,
she told me
not to inform
her family about this yet.
Who exactly
set Yan Xing up?
You must find out.
We also believe
that Yan Xing wouldn't kill anyone.
But the person who arrested her
is Princess Runing.
I'm afraid
it won't be easy to investigate.
What's so difficult about it?
We have both witnesses and physical evidence.
A life for a life.
It's only right and proper.
You...
Lord Lai,
I wonder why you've come to the prison of the Ministry of Justice
so late at night.
The incident at Mingsheng Temple
involves a royal princess.
The Grand Empress Dowager wants to interrogate
the murderer, Yan Xing.
What are you waiting for?
Bring the prisoner.
Yes.
Wait.
What do you mean by this, Grand Commander Shen?
Are you trying to shield your wife
and obstruct the trial?
Is this a perversion of justice?
Is the Imperial Investigation Department's raid on the prison
Her Majesty's will,
or are you abusing your favor
and ignoring the law?
The Imperial Investigation Department
has always been loyal to Her Majesty.
Grand Commander Shen, your words
are quite slanderous.
As for today's matter,
I must personally handle it
to fulfill Her Majesty's
long-standing trust.
I will investigate this matter myself.
Lord Lai,
you may leave.
Guard this place well.
If anyone dares to approach,
consider it a jailbreak attempt
and show no mercy.
Yes!
I didn't expect
you'd be so convinced that
Mrs. Shen isn't the murderer.
I wonder
when Her Majesty learns of this tomorrow,
will she be moved by
your deep marital affection,
or will she order me to carry out the sentence?
One night.
I suggest you
make the most of
this night of intimacy.
Let's go.
We'll return tomorrow.
What are you doing here
-in the middle of the night?
-Wu.
Stop talking.
Just come with me.
Can't it wait until tomorrow?
Grand Commander.
Jing Lin,
you saw with your own eyes that day
after Yan Xing left the Chen's Mansion,
she seemed to be chasing someone,
riding all the way to the woods west of the city.
Yes.
Yan Xing said
she discovered
the Chen family's servant had forged a testimony,
so she went to the Chen's Mansion
and found he was trying to escape.
So she chased him all the way to Mingsheng Temple.
That's right.
That's exactly what Yan Xing said.
Then something's not right.
What's wrong?
Jing Lin.
Lift your foot.
I see.
The woods in the west of the city are muddy.
If one were riding a fast horse,
the trouser cuffs couldn't be this clean.
I must have dirtied my shoes
on the way to Mingsheng Temple
following Madam.
But the servant's shoes
are spotless.
So how did the body
end up at Mingsheng Temple?
This smell...
Could it be...
The Mingsheng Temple case
has many suspicious points.
Before tomorrow,
no one is allowed to interrogate the suspect.
But what if...
If a single hair of Yan Xing
is missing in the prison,
I'll hold you accountable.
Grand Commander,
where should we investigate next?
The source of the mistake.
[Not entering the cycle of reincarnation.
Immortal reincarnation]
[Moths to a flame
Born at dawn, dead by dusk]
Born at dawn, dead by dusk
Not entering the cycle of reincarnation.
Immortal reincarnation]
This powder is very similar to
the one that appeared at Jinxiu Workshop.
Could it be
that Madam was set up
right here?
Fire moths! Fire moths! Fire moths!
What was originally placed here?
Grand Commander,
there doesn't seem to be any
signs of searching or fighting here.
So much blood.
It looks like this is
the scene of the crime.
Then how did
the victim end up at Mingsheng Temple?
It's a box.
[Mingsheng Temple]
Grand Commander,
this is Prince Xian's whereabouts from last night.
[Prince Xian met Princess Runing privately at Mingsheng Temple last night.]
As expected.
If they find out
that you had someone
keep an eye on Prince Xian,
-I'm afraid...
-Saving her is the priority.
[Prince Xian met Princess Runing privately at Mingsheng Temple last night.]
It seems I'll have to meet
this Princess Runing myself.
[Mingsheng Temple]
I am Shen Du, the Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau.
Greetings to Your Highness.
Grand Commander Shen,
known as the renowned White Ghost.
Who are you here
to arrest today?
Your Highness misunderstands.
I came today to ask for a favor.
Grand Commander, you jest.
I am no longer a princess,
just a commoner now.
What favor could you possibly want from me?
Please leave.
Your Highness,
please hear my request.
If it's about court matters,
they have nothing to do with me anymore.
There's no need for you to continue.
It's a personal family matter of mine.
Family matter?
Yesterday, my wife was framed by someone
and accidentally trespassed into Mingsheng Temple.
Now she's imprisoned.
I hope Your Highness can show leniency.
I can't believe you're here
for your wife.
This is quite different from the rumors about
the ruthless White Ghost.
You want me to
release your wife?
I want you to give me the truth.
What do you mean?
Are you saying I slandered
your wife?
Your Highness certainly wouldn't slander intentionally,
but if you're trying to protect someone,
you might withhold some information.
Nonsense.
I'm tired.
Please leave.
At the time of the incident,
were you really alone at Mingsheng Temple?
No one else came here?
The Grand Empress Dowager has confined you.
If she knew about your secret meeting with the Prince Xian,
I wonder how she would feel.
Are you threatening me?
I just want the truth.
He just
came to visit his lonely
and helpless aunt,
brought some items,
and had a cup of tea.
He never talked about state affairs,
nor did he have any ulterior motives.
This is just
a family courtesy.
Is that so hard to believe?
Prince Xian values family bonds,
but others
might not see it that way.
Sometimes,
just one word
can cause someone to die unjustly.
Your Highness, please tell me the truth
and clear my wife's name.
Open it.
Indeed,
I didn't see your wife kill anyone with my own eyes.
When I arrived,
the hall only
had her and the body.
I didn't want others to know
that Prince Xian had been there,
so I let them
leave through the back door first.
Later, when I checked the back door,
I did find
signs of forced entry.
Among the items
Prince Xian brought,
I found this box,
but I have no idea where it came from.
Thank you for telling the truth.
I apologize for any offense I may have caused today.
Grand Commander, you'd better watch yourself.
If anything happens to Prince Xian,
I will certainly inform Her Majesty
about your surveillance of the royal family.
Your Highness, do you think
I would be so bold
as to act on my own?
I hope that from now on,
we'll have more peaceful days.
Your Highness, don't you want to know
the truth about the Jinxiu Workshop case from back then?
What good would knowing the truth do?
The dead
can never come back.
The deceased have passed on
and found peace.
It's nothing more than
a comforting phrase for the living.
What really happened with that case?
No one dared to investigate it back then.
What can be done about it now?
I, Shen Du, promise today
to thoroughly investigate what happened back then
and reveal the truth.
Very well.
Then I'll wait for your truth.
Your Highness,
Mingsheng Temple is a place of controversy.
If Her Majesty learns
that you've been there,
she will surely accuse you of
forming factions
and plotting treason.
When one wants to frame someone,
they'll always find a way.
Back then, my aunt
was involved in the Jinxiu Workshop bloodshed
all because of a single piece of clothing.
Be careful with your words, Your Highness.
Be careful.
You've just made a charitable gesture for disaster relief,
which pleased Her Majesty.
You must not do
anything to upset Her Majesty.
Don't neglect the small details.
You might lose the big picture because of small mistakes.
Shen Du has long been aware of this matter,
yet he didn't report it.
He's quite cunning.
It's almost dawn.
Why hasn't Grand Commander Shen returned yet?
It's about time.
Bring out the prisoner.
You'er quite stubborn, aren't you?
I remember back then,
you were defeated by Shen Du.
Now you're following his orders.
By the Grand Empress Dowager's decree,
Lord Lai is to conduct the interrogation at 9 a.m.
The prisoner must not
be brought before then.
You constable,
how dare you obstruct the Imperial Investigation Department's business?
Let me see just
how tough
you are.
Lord Lai, you're quite imposing.
But you seem
a bit too eager.
Working for Her Majesty,
I should certainly do my utmost.
I now announce Her Majesty's decree.
The Mingsheng Temple case has many suspicious points.
It is now fully entrusted to the Imperial Security Bureau
for a full investigation.
Grand Commander Shen,
you're perfect in time.
Let's go.
Why isn't she coming out yet?
Please, please.
Come out quickly.
Xing,
you're finally out.
I was so worried about you.
Come on,
sweep the bad luck away.
It's good that you
came out safe and sound.
Well,
what case were you investigating
that got you into trouble?
But
it's good that you came out safe and sound.
Do you know
how worried I was
when I heard you were
arrested for murder?
Sweep here and there
to ward off bad luck.
Turn around, turn around.
I'm blessed with good fortune.
Now the case's cleared up,
so I was released.
If it weren't for Grand Commander Shen
going to find Princess Runing
to explain the situation,
and finding the box used to transport the body
by those who framed you
in the woods behind
Mingsheng Temple,
you wouldn't have
been released so easily.
He went to find the Princess?
What did you just say?
The box used to transport the body
was thrown into the woods?
That's not right.
What's not right?
You must have been terrified.
It's okay now.
Oh, right,
Xu and Jiang Langxing
have gone to investigate
new leads.
I heard that
the dead servant of the Chen family
had been stealing from the Chen's assets
while Chen Shoujie was confused.
Later, Mrs. Chen discovered it.
So he betrayed his master.
He probably colluded with
someone outside
and struck a fatal blow.
It's a pity there's no one left to testify.
Yan Xing.
Grand Commander.
Are you here to take Xing back home?
Back home?
I'm full of energy right now.
I'm going to investigate the case
and clear my own name.
What are you doing?
From now on,
you're not allowed to investigate this case.
I've already come this far in the investigation.
How can you expect me
to back out now?
Also,
the body of the Chen family's servant
should be at the Ministry of Justice.
I must find clues
from his body.
I said you can't investigate.
The real culprit used the servant
to lure me to Mingsheng Temple,
obviously trying to make me
suspect Princess Runing.
Princess Runing
hasn't left Mingsheng Temple in years.
Who would want to
drag her into this?
Enough.
Is it because it might be related to the royal family
that you want me to give up the investigation?
Leave this matter to me.
I will handle it properly.
I just want to uncover the truth of the case.
Since you, Grand Commander Shen,
are so timid,
and afraid of the powerful,
fine.
I'll investigate this case myself.
You can just
keep walking
your own path.
So this is what you think of me.
Aren't you always afraid
of being implicated by others?
Then let's divorce right now.
So you won't have to write
a confession later.
Xing,
what should we do now?
Where are you going?
To examine the body.
Shen Du checked the body before.
His shoes
weren't dirty with forest mud.
The body was moved
to Mingsheng Temple after death.
What?
Did you find something?
Come and smell this.
This smell
is from something used to delay the body's decay.
He was
already dead when I arrived at
Chen Shoujie's residence.
As for what happened afterwards,
although I witnessed it with my own eyes,
I can't be certain
that it was reality.
Are you saying
that everything you saw was an illusion?
What kind of thing
or drug could
control people's minds like that?
The world is vast
and full of wonders.
I suppose
it's far beyond our understanding.
Moreover,
I'm more worried that
the method this servant used
to delay
the body's decay
is the same as what Mrs. Tang
used back then.
Do you believe there's a way
to bring the dead back to life?
Are you worried that Chen Huo'e
might actually come back from the dead
like people say?
Yes.
I don't believe it.
That's why I must find the truth.
So,
you had an argument with your husband
and ran away from home?
I'm just afraid that
without
White Ghost's protection,
someone might bully you.
I'm not afraid.
I still have you guys, right?
If you go home and your mother finds out,
she'll definitely scold you.
Don't worry,
I've already figured out where to go.
[History Archive]
This place holds all the case files
from the Ministry of Justice over the years.
I'm sure I can
find some clues here.
Miss Yan.
Official Ji.
Why are you coming here so late?
Official Ji,
I want to look for
all the records around
[Ji Fangming, Director of History Archive]
the time of the Jinxiu Workshop case.
You've been in charge of the History Archive for years.
Do you know where they might be?
Jinxiu Workshop...
It's been quite a while.
Perhaps over there.
You can take a look.
Thank you.
This scent...
Where have I smelled it before?
Miss Yan.
Be careful with the fire.
Thank you.
I'll be very cautious.
Aren't you always afraid
of being implicated by others?
Then let's divorce right now.
So you won't have to write
a confession later.
Mother.
Oranges.
The branches of the orange tree outside the wall
just fell into the garden.
♫For the sake of an end, I embraced silence and became a Shura♫
I know you like oranges,
so I picked some for you.
♫Love is elusive, piercing you and burning me♫
Have you written
what I asked you to write?
I won't write it.
I can't write it either.
♫Along the way, flowers bloom and fall, rain pours heavily♫
Father served as an official his whole life with integrity.
He never did anything
♫Lights will cross♫
against the Shen family's ancestral rules.
Father was framed.
♫You are my destination♫
How could I admit
those false charges on behalf of him?
Shut up!
You are a criminal by association.
♫Who will save me from my loneliness and confusion?♫
If you don't distance yourself from the Shen family,
♫Understanding my fragility, no words are needed♫
you will never have
a chance to rise again!
♫Who will save me from my panic and obsession?♫
But how could I
♫Sheltering my solitude, never letting me fall♫
live for myself alone
and let Father be condemned by the world?
♫The chains of fate between us cannot be broken♫
Rather than that,
I'd rather die like Father
to prove my innocence.
♫Holding the warmth you once gave♫
But if even you die too,
♫Guiding me to see myself, the person I truly am♫
this wrongful case
will truly be settled.
Shen Du,
do you really want them
♫Who will save me from right and wrong?♫
to remain restless
in the afterlife?
♫Tossed in the sea of people, just hold me tight♫
If you don't write that confession,
♫Who will save me from grudges and karma?♫
I'm no longer
♫Healing my sorrow, never letting me escape♫
your mother from now on.
♫The past fades, how many times have we met?♫
For your father's innocence,
for the Shen family's honor,
♫Who can break free from destiny?♫
no matter how difficult,
or dangerous it is,
♫I'll cross rivers and leap into fire for you♫
you must keep going.